Guide to the Warren Tucker Photograph Albums
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Warren Tucker photograph albums
1907-1933
PC0051
Tucker, Warren
0.75 Linear feet
The collection consists of two albums of photographs (1909-1912) and three albums containing photonegatives (1907-1933). Images relating to Stanford date from 1907 to 1912 and include views of the Quad, the Mausoleum, Lake Lagunita, the class of 1910 plugs [top hats] and the Plug Ugly rush, dormitory rooms in Encina Hall, athletics, the Big Game bonfire, and other student amusements. Identified students include Herbert Lincoln Hubbard, Harry Robert Person, and Walter Elliot. Other subjects (primarily represented among the negatives) include family members, 1908-33; camping trips and family vacations in the Sierra Mountains, Lake Tahoe and Yosemite National Park, 1908-1931; and train wrecks in Arizona, 1913-1914.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Doris Tucker Shepherd, 1992.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Warren Tucker graduated from Stanford University in 1912, with an a.b. in pre-law. He married Edith G. Engelhard, also of the class of 1912, and pursued a real estate career in Oakland, California.
Description of the Collection
The collection consists of two albums of photographs (1909-1912) and three albums containing photonegatives (1907-1933). Images relating to Stanford date from 1907 to 1912 and include views of the Quad, the Mausoleum, Lake Lagunita, the class of 1910 plugs [top hats] and the Plug Ugly rush, dormitory rooms in Encina Hall, athletics, the Big Game bonfire, and other student amusements. Identified students include Herbert Lincoln Hubbard, Harry Robert Person, and Walter Elliot. Other subjects (primarily represented among the negatives) include family members, 1908-33; camping trips and family vacations in the Sierra Mountains, Lake Tahoe and Yosemite National Park, 1908-1931; and train wrecks in Arizona, 1913-1914.
Access Terms
Elliot, Walter.; Hubbard, Herbert Lincoln.; Person, Harry Robert.; Tucker, Warren; Photonegatives; Railroads--Accidents--Photographs.; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) --Photographs.
Collection Contents
- Negatives
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Quad (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Quad (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Quad (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Quad (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Mausoleum (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Edna (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: Aunt Dell (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - First visit to Stanford, 1907: on S. F. Bay Ferry Boat (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Richelieu cast, Person and Barclew, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Richelieu cast, Tucker and Barclew, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Richelieu cast, Person, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Richelieu cast, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Palo Alto tree, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Herbert L. Hubbard at Mausoleum, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Class of 1910 plugs, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Given the Hook poster, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Angel of Grief, circa 1908 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rule of 12 poster, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lake Lagunita, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lake Lagunita, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hubbardís room, Thanksgiving, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Building of the bonfire, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Building of the bonfire, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hauser, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hauser, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - In hospital, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - In hospital, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Group in room, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Elliots room, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Thompson and Hill, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Initiation, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hubbard and Clark, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Roth; initiation, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Hauser, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Hubbardís room (Encina Hall): Hubbard, Hays & Person (?), 1909 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Hubbardís room (Encina Hall): Tucker, Hubbard, Hays, and Clark, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Leaving for S[tanford] with R. Paine, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Room at S[Stanford], Person and Tucker playing cards, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Room at S[Stanford], Person and Tucker playing cards, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - After rush, Hubbard, Person, Tucker, Sherman, circa 1908 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Kodak negative album containing non-Stanford negatives: Redlands ranch, camping trip in mountains, family and friends, 1908 (Box 1)
  - Kodak negative album containing non-Stanford negatives: family in Burlingame, 1912, scenes in Arizona and train wrecks, 1913-14, house in Salt Lake City, 1916, Custerís battlefield, 1916, Yosemite National Park, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Kodak negative album containing non-Stanford negatives: family members, 1929-33, Yosemite National Park, 1930, Lake Tahoe, 1931, vacation on Middle Fork of the San Joaquin, 1931 (Box 2)
- Photoprints
  - Photograph album: family images and student life 1908-09 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photograph album: images of student life and of a variety of hikes, rides, and other excursions 1909-1912 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Loose photos from album (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Article on Delta Chi fraternity house at Stanford, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 4)